Choral Octavos by Yale Alumni
Yale University Music Library
Choral Octavos by Yale Alumni
1897-1972
Misc. Ms. 57
Yale University Music Library
1
(2 boxes)
Choral works by alumni and faculty of the Yale School of Music
Archer, Violet, 1913-2000
Barnard, Parke S.
Bartholomew, Marshall, 1885-1978
Baumgartner, H. Leroy (Hope Leroy), 1891-1969
Bingham, Seth, 1882-1972
Boatwright, Howard, 1918-1999
Buttolph, David, 1902-1983
Byles, G. Huntington
Carr, Arthur George
Coe, Kenton, 1930-
Crain, Gordon Ferris
Davison, John (John H.), 1930-1999
Di Bonaventura, Sam
Diemer, Emma Lou, 1927-
Donovan, Richard, 1891-1970
Goodman, Joseph, 1918-2014
Jouard, Paul
Kraehenbuehl, David
Lewin, Frank
Lewis, Harold Merrills, 1908-
Nagel, Robert, 1924-
Parker, Horatio W. (Horatio William), 1863-1919
Pauly, Reinhard G.
Prince, Philip A.
Rhea, Arthur D.
Rockwood, Gay Hylander
Shackford, Charles
Sly, Albert
Smith, David Stanley, 1877-1949
Stark, Richard B.
Thomas, Paul, 1919-
Thorne, Francis, 1922-
Tuttle, Lloyd B.
Work, John W. (John Wesley), 1901-1967
York, David Stanley
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was established in the Music Library of Yale University by Luther Noss in 1974.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by composer.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of 178 choral works, nearly all of them composed by alumni of the Yale School of Music; the faculty of the School is also represented. The collection was assembled by Luther Noss and consists primarily of published octavos; some reproductions of manuscript scores are also included.
Choruses, Sacred (Men's voices); Choruses, sacred (mixed voices); Choruses, Sacred (Women's voices); Choruses, Secular (Men's voices); Choruses, secular (mixed voices); Choruses, Secular (Women's voices); Yale School of Music
- Violet Archer
  General
  Mus. B. 1948, Mus. M. 1949
  - I Will Lift Up Mine Eyes (Box 1, Folder 1)
    A General Anthem for SATB and Organ
    Text: Psalm 121
    (Commissioned by the Edmonton Centre of the Royal Canadian College of Organists for the Centennial Year)
    Waterloo Music Company Limited (1969) Waterloo - Ontario - Canada
  - O Lord, Thou Hast Searched Me and Known Me (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Anthem for SATB and Organ
    Text: Psalm 139
- Parke S. Barnard
  Mus. B. 1950
  - Ah, Dearest Jesus (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Christmas Carol for Mixed Voices, à cappella, SATB
    Text: Martin Luther
    Translated by Catherine Winkworth
    Hall & McCreary Company, (1950) Chicago, Illinois
  - Auditui (Box 1, Folder 2)
    for voices - SSTBB
    Text: Psalm 50
    Signed by composer: "psb 1/10/53"
    (Photographic reproduction)
  - Christ Is Arisen, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Set for SATB, à cappella
    Inscribed by composer: "For the First Lutheran Choir, West Haven, Conn., psb, 3/2/53"
  - God Be Merciful Unto Us (Box 1, Folder 2)
    For Mixed Voices, SSATB
    Text: Psalm 67
    Summy-Birchard Publishing Company (1960) Evanston, Illinois
  - Hodie Christus Natus Est, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Motet for SAATB
    Signed by composer: "psb, 11/4/52"
  - I Sing of a Maiden (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Carol for SSAA
    Text: Anonymous XV Century
    Inscribed by composer: "For the Albertus Magnus College Chorus - 1951, psb, 11/26/51"
  - The Nicene Creed (Box 1, Folder 2)
    SATB with Tenor Solo
    Inscribed by composer: "For the First Lutheran Choir, West Haven, Conn., 7 March, 1952, psb"
  - Puer Natus (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Set for Unmixed Voices
    Melodies: Anonymous (1545-1561)
    Text: Anonymous (1545)
    English version - psb
    Signed by composer: "psb, 10/10/51"
  - What Child Is This: "Greensleeves", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Set for Mixed Voices SATB
    Signed by composer: "psb, 10/16/51"
- Marshall Bartholomew
  Ph.D. 1907, Faculty - 1921-1953
  - Along The Street I Hear (Burgundian Carol) / Arranged by Marshall Bartholomew (Box 1, Folder 3)
    For Chorus Voices, Unaccompanied
    Text: Bernard De La Monnoye
    English Version: Alfred R. Bellinger
    Galaxy Music Corporation (1947), 50 West 24th Street, New York
  - The Ancient Hills op. 19, No. 1 / Edited by Marshall Bartholomew, Johansen, David Monrad (Box 1, Folder 3)
    For Chorus of Men's Voices, Unaccompanied
    Text: Ivar Aasen
    English Version: Robert B. Falk
    Galaxy Music Corporation (1942), 17 West 46th Street, New York
  - A Ballynure Ballad / Arranged by Marshall Bartholomew (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Arranged for four-part Chorus of men
    Tune and Text from "Irish Country Songs, Vol. I," edited, arranged and for the most part collected by Herbert Hughes, published by Boosey & Hawkes
    Mercury Music Corporation (1951), New York. N.Y.
  - The Bells in the Steeple / Edited by Marshall Bartholomew, Sammartini, Giuseppe, 1693-1750 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Glee for Male Voices, TBB
    Mercury Music Corporation (1949), 47 W. 63rd St., New York 23, N.Y.
  - Daybreak by the Sea (Gryning Vid Havet) / Edited by Marshall Bartholomew, Alfvén, Hugo (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Text: Sten Selander
    English Version: George Sjöblom, Marshall Kernochan
    Galaxy Music Corporation (1941), New York
  - How Merrily We Live / Edited by Marshall Bartholomew, Michael Este (1600) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Madrigal for Male Voices, TBB
    Mercury Music Corporation (1949), 47 w. 63rd St., New York 23, N.Y.
  - Loveliest of Women (Dejligste Blandt Kvinder) / Arranged by Marshall Bartholomew, Grieg, Edvard (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Hymn to the Virgin
    For Chorus of Ments Voices, Unaccompanied
    Galaxy Music Corporation (1940), New York
  - Old Neighbors Op. 19, No. 2 / Edited by Marshall Bartholomew, Johansen, David Monrad (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Galaxy Music Corporation (1944), New York
  - Ten Glees, Madrigals, and Airs / Edited by Marshall Bartholomew (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Scope and Contents
    1. Ah. How Gladly We Believe / Purcell (1658-1695)
    2. Amo, Amas, I Love a Lass / Anonymous (1764)
    3. Happy Are We Met / Anonymous (1764)
    4. How Merrily We Live / Este (1600)
    5. Punch, An Emblem of the Medium of Life / Arne (1710-1778)
    6. The Bells of the Steeple / Sammartini (1693-1750)
    7. The Captive Lover / Lawes (1653)
    8. Turn, Amarillis, To Thy Swain / Brewer (1667)
    9. We Be Soldiers Three / Anonymous (1614)
    10. Which Is The Properest Day To Drink? / Arne (1765)
    For Three-Part Chorus of Men's Voices
    Music Press, Inc. (1949), 130 W. 56 St., New York
  - This Joyful Easter Tide / Arranged by Marshall Bartholomew (1957) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Tune from David's Psalmen Amsterdam, 1685
    From the Cowley Carol Book, No. 51
    Harmonized for TTBB
    (Holograph)
    Included with this holograph: autograph letter signed to Luther Noss, 4/7/57
  - Three Negro Spirituals / Arranged by Marshall Bartholomew (Box 1, Folder 3)
    1. Ready When He Comes
    2. Roll, Jordan, Roll
    3. Bones Come A-Knittin'
    For Four-Part Chorus of Men's Voices, Unaccompanied
    G. Schirmer, Inc. (1934), New York
  - Two Negro Spirituals / Arranged by Marshall Bartholomew (Box 1, Folder 3)
    1. Old Ark's A-Moverin'
    2. Steal Away
  - Were You There? / Negro Spiritual Arranged by Marshall Bartholomew (Box 1, Folder 3)
    For Full Chorus of Men's Voices With Alto Solo, à cappella
    G. Schirmer, Inc. (1948), New York
  - What Shall We Do With a Drunken Sailor? / Arranged by Marshall Bartholomew, Chantey, Sea (Box 1, Folder 3)
    For Four-Part Chorus of Men's Voices
    G. Schirmer, Inc. (1930), New York
- H. Leroy Baumgartner
  Mus. B. 1916, Faculty 1919-1960
  - Fight the Good Fight Op. 51 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    For Men's Chorus with Organ Accompaniment
    Text: John S.B. Monsell (1863)
  - From the Words of Jeremiah Op. 10, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Anthem for TTBB with Accompaniment for Organ and Three Pedal-Kettle drums
    Text: Revised Standard Version of the Bible Jeremiah 17: verses 5-10 and 14
  - I Sought the Lord Op. 85, No. 1, 1960, revised - 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Three Psalms for Mixed Voices, Unaccompanied
    Text: Revised Standard Version of the Bible Psalm 314: verses 4, 5, 8, 15, 18, 19
  - There Was Only Love in that Stable Place Op. 53 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Carol for Christmas or Epiphany
    SATB with Soprano Solo
    Text: Edith Shaw Butler in "The High Call"
    C.C. Birchard & Company (1954) Boston, Mass.
- Seth Bingham
  B.A. 1904, Mus. B. 1908
  - Days of Forty-Nine (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Arranged by Seth Bingham for Men's Voices, with Baritone Solo
    H.W. Gray Co. (1930) New York
  - Dogie Song (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Arranged by Seth Bingham for Men's Voices, with Bass Solo
  - The Dying Cowboy (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Arranged by Seth Bingham for Men's Voices, with Baritone or Tenor Solo
  - Fuller and Warren (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Arranged by Seth Bingham for Men's Voices, with Tenor or Bass Solos
  - Hymn to Pan Op. 21, No. 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Unaccompanied Three-Part Chorus for Women's Voices
    Text: Beaumont and Fletcher
    H.W. Gray Co. (1921) New York
  - Jubilate Deo in B-flat (O Be Joyful in the Lord) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    For Chorus of Mixed Voices with Organ Accompaniment
    Boston Music Co. (1946) Boston, Mass.
  - Personent Hodie (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Medieval Christmas Carol
    Arranged with English Text for Mixed Chorus by Seth Bingham
    H.W. Gray Co. (1943) New York
  - Root Hog or Die (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Arranged by Seth Bingham for Men's Voices with Baritone Solo
  - Rosalynd's Madrigal Op. 22, No. 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Unaccompanied Four Part Chorus for Women's Voices
    Text: Thomas Lodge
  - Spring, the Sweet Spring Op. 21, No. 5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Unaccompanied Three part Chorus for Women's Voices
    Text: Thomas Nash
- Howard Boatwright
  Mus. B. 1947, Mus. M. 1948, Faculty - 1948-1964
  - An Advent Hymn, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Text: Latin, 9th Century, Hymnal Version, 1940, after J.M. Neale
    Signed by composer: "For the Choir of St. Thomas's Church, Howard Boatwright, New Haven, Conn., December 9, 1956"
  - Ah, Holy Jesus, How Hast Thou Offended / Hymn No. 2 from "The Passion According to St. Matthew," by Howard Boatwright (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Chorale for Four-part Chorus of Mixed Voices, à cappella
    Text: Johann Heermann, 1623
    Translation: Robert Bridges (1844-1930)
    E.C. Schirmer Music Co. (1966)
    600 Washington Street
    Boston, Mass.
  - All Praise to Thee / Hymn No. 5 from "The Passion According to St. Matthew," by Howard Boatwright (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Hymn for Four-part Chorus of Mixed Voices, à cappella
    Text: F. Bland Tucker, 1938
    E.C. Schirmer Music Co. (1966), 600 Washington Street, Boston, Mass.
  - Alone Thou Goest Forth, O Lord / Hymn No. 6 from "The Passion According to St. Matthew," by Howard Boatwright (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Motet for Four-part Chorus of Mixed Voices, à cappella
    Text: Peter Abelard, 1079-1142
    Translation: F. Bland Tucker, 1938
  - Creator of the Stars of Night (Conditor alme siderum) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Advent Hymn for Four-part Chorus of Mixed Voices, à cappella
    Text: English Version after J.M. Neale
    E.C. Schirmer Music Co. (1959), 221 Columbus Avenue, Boston, Mass.
  - For Sins of Heedless Word and Deed / Hymn No. 4 from "The Passion According to St. Matthew," by Howard Boatright (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Text: William Boyd Carpenter (1841-1918)
  - Go to Dark Gethsemane / Hymn No. 1 from "The Passion According to St. Matthew," by Howard Boatwright (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Hymn for Four-part Chorus of Mixed Voices, with Descant and Organ
    Text: James Montgomery (1771-1854), adapted by Howard Boatwright, 1963
  - God Is Our Refuge and Strength (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Motet for Four-part chorus of Mixed Voices, à cappella
    Text: Psalm XLVI
  - Hear My Cry, O God (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Text: Psalm LXI: 1-4
    (2 copies)
  - Jesus All Thy Labor Vast / Hymn No. 10 from "The passion According to St. Matthew," by Howard Boatwright (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Text: Thomas Benson Pollack, 1870
  - Morning Hymn / Variations based on Jam Lucis Orto Sidere, 7th C.? (Box 1, Folder 6)
    For Four-part Chorus of Mixed Voices, à cappella
    English version by J.M. Neale
  - Nunc Sancte Nobis Spiritus (Come, Holy Spirit) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Text: Attributed to St. Ambrose
    English version by Howard Boatwright
  - O Sacred Head, Sore Wounded / Hymn No. 8 from "The Passion According to St. Matthew," by Howard Boatwright (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Text: Paul Gerhardt, 1656
    Melody: Passion Chorale - Hans Leo Hassler, 1601, adapted by J.S. Bach
  - Psalm 61, for Mixed Chorus (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Signed by composer: "Howard Boatwright, April 10, 1951, New Haven, Conn., revised for the Yale Choral Society March, 1952."
  - The Royal Banners Forward Go / Hymn No. 7 from "The Passion According to St. Matthew," by Howard Boatwright (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Text: Venantius Honorius Fortunatus, 596
    Hymnal version, 1940
    Melody: Puer Nobis - adapted by M. Praetorius, 1609
  - A Short Mass in F / Cantus Firmus, Merbecke, 1549 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Signed by composer: "Howard Boatwright, July 1951, New Haven, Conn."
  - Sing, My Tongue, the Glorious Battle / Hymn No. 11 from "The Passion According to St. Matthew," by Howard Boatwright (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Text: Venantius Honorious Fortunatus, 596
    Hymnal version, 1940, after J.M. Neale
    Melody: Dulce Carmen - An essay on the Church Plain Chant, 1782
    E.C. Schirmer Music Co. (1966), 600 Washington Avenue, Boston, Mass.
  - Star in the East (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Text: Reginald Heber, 1783-1826
  - When I Survey the Wondrous Cross / Hymn No. 9 from "The Passion According to St. Matthew," by Howard Boatwright (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Text: Isaac Watts, 1707
    Melody: Guidetti - Medieval, arr. by G. Guidetti, 1582
  - Who Was the Guilty? / Hymn No. 3 from "The Passion According to St. Matthew," by Howard Boatwright (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Translation by Robert Bridges (1844-1930)
    Melody: Herzliebster Jesu - Johann Crueger, 1640
- David Buttolph
  B.A. 1944
  - He Is Born, the Beloved Child / Il est né, le divin enfant (Box 1, Folder 7)
    For Treble Voices with 4 horns or piano
    Arrangement and English Translation by David Buttolph
    Galaxy Music Corporation (1965), New York
- Huntington Byles
  Mus. B. 1931
  - Sower and Reaper - Thou, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Hymn - Anthem founded on chorale by J.S. Bach
    Poem by James R. Woodford
    Variations by G. Huntington Byles
- Arthur Carr
  Mus. B. 1932
  - The Mountain (Box 1, Folder 7)
    For Women's Voices (SSAA) with Piano Accompaniment
    Poem by Mikhail Lermontov
    Translated by Max Eastman
    Galaxy Music Corporation (1932), 2 East 46th Street, New York
- Kenton Coe
  B.A. 1953
  - Psalm 67, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    SATB
- Gordon Ferris Crain
  Mus. B. 1952
  - Requiem Mass (Box 1, Folder 7)
- John Davison
  B.A. 1952
  - Sanctus, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    (Photographic reproductions)
- Sam Di Bonaventura
  Mus. B. 1953, Mus. M. 1954
  - Ave Regina Caelorum (Box 1, Folder 7)
    (Mimeograph reproduction)
- Emma Lou Diemer
  Mus. B. 1949, Mus. M. 1950
  - Three Choruses for Mixed Voices, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    I. "Lament" Words: E. Millay
    II. "Between Two Hills" Words: C. Sandburg
    III. "The Faëry Forest" Words: S. Teasdale
- Richard F. Donovan
  Mus. B. 1922, Faculty 1928-1960
  - Fantasy on American Folk Ballads (Box 1, Folder 8)
    For Men's Voices and Piano Four Hands
    J. Fischer & Bro. (1941), 119 West 40th Street, New York, N.Y.
  - Good Ale (Box 1, Folder 8)
    For Four-part Chorus of Men's Voices with Piano Accompaniment, TTBB
    Poem by John Still (1543?-1608)
    Carl Fischer, Inc. (1947), New York
  - How Great, O Lord, Is Thy Goodness (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Anthem for Chorus of Mixed Voices with Soprano and Baritone Soli
    Text: Psalm xxxi. 19, Proverbs iii. 17
    Boston Music Co. (1923), Boston, Mass.
  - Hymn to the Night (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Unaccompanied Chorus of Women's Voices, SSA
    Text: Henry Wadsworth Longfellow
    J. Fischer & Bro. (1947), 119 West 40th Street, New York
  - I'll Go to Bethlehem / Czecho-Slovakian Carol (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Arranged for SATB by Richard Donovan
    English version by Edward Bliss Reed
    Stainer & Bell Ltd. (1931), 58, Berners Street, London, England
  - Jacques, Come Here (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Text: French Carol 1555
    Translated by Edward Bliss Reed
  - Lulling Her Child / Czecho-Slovakian Carol (Box 1, Folder 8)
    English Version by Edward Bliss Reed
  - Saviour, When Night Involves the Skies (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Unaccompanied Anthem for SATB
    Text: T. Gisborne
    H.W. Gray Co. (1920), New York
- Joseph Goodman
  Mus. B. 1940
  - Before the Ending of the Day (Box 1, Folder 9)
    For Mixed Chorus (SATB) à cappella
    Text: Latin, c 7th Century
    Adapted from John Mason Neale, 1851.
    Mercury Music Corporation (1966), New York
  - Crucem Tuam Adoramus (We Venerate Thy Cross) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Antiphon for Good Friday, for Four-Part Chorus of Mixed Voices à cappella
    English text from the Anglican Missal
    Associated Music Publishers, Inc. (1961), New York
  - Laudate Dominum (Box 1, Folder 9)
    For Four-Part Chorus of Mixed Voices à cappella with Soprano Solo ad lib.
    Text: Psalm 116 (Liber Usualis)
    Associated Music Publishers, Inc. (1958), New York
  - O King Enthroned on High (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Text: from Greek Pentecostarion, c.8th Century
    Translation: John Brownlie, English Hymnal, 1906
  - O Trinity of Blessed Light (Box 1, Folder 9)
    For Mixed Chorus SATB à cappella
    Text: O Lux beata, Trinitas, St. Ambrose (?)
    Translation: John Mason Neale, 1851
  - Song in the Wood (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Text: T. Fletcher (c. 1620)
    Mercury Music Corporation (1952), New York
  - That Easter Day with Joy was Bright (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Text: Latin, 5th Century
    Adapted from John Mason Neale, 1851
  - Three Motets for Benediction (Box 1, Folder 9)
    I. O Salutaris Hostia
    II. Jesu, Rex Admirabilis
    III. Tantum Ergo
    SATB, à cappella
- Paul Jouard
  Mus. B. 1919, Mus. M. 1950
  - Hosanna Filio David, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    SSATTB
    Text: Adapted from the St. Gregory Hymnal, '20
- David Kraehenbuehl
  Mus. B. 1918, Mus. M. 1949, Faculty - 1953-1960
  - Veni Sancte Spiritus (Box 1, Folder 10)
    An Anthem for Male Chorus à cappella
    Inscribed by composer: "The Feast of St. Gregory the Great, March 12, 1960"
- Frank Lewin
  Mus. B. 1951, Faculty - 1971-
  - Psalm 121 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Century Letter Company (1946), 110 West 47th Street, New York 19
- Merrills Lewis
  Mus. B. 1931, Mus. M. 1936
  - From the South - A Sacred Rhapsody (Box 1, Folder 11)
    For Chorus and Orchestra
    Based upon Southern Folk Hymn Tunes: Dunlap's Creek - Wings of the Morning - Kedron - Foundation - Garden Hymn
    Choral Press (1952), 1311 North Highland Avenue, Hollywood 28, Calif.
  - The Lamb (Box 1, Folder 11)
    For Chorus of Mixed Voices Unaccompanied
    Text: William Blake
    Galaxy Music Corporation (1941), 17 West 46th Street, New York
  - This is America (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Chorus for Mixed Voices with Accompaniment for Piano or Orchestra
    Text: Katharine Janeway Conger
    H.W. Gray Co. (1943), New York
- Robert Nagel
  Faculty - 1956-
  - Triptych (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Mixed Chorus (SATB) and Organ or Piano and/or Brass Quartet
    Text: From the New Testament
    Marks Music Corporation (1972), 136 West 52nd Street New York, N.Y. 10019
- Horatio Parker
  Dean - 1894-1920
  - A.D. 1919 Op. 84 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    SATB and Piano
    Text: Brian Hooker
    Yale University Press (1919), New Haven, Conn.
  - Come Away! Op. 54 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Part-Song for SATB
    Text: Anonymous from John Dowland's First Book of Songs or Airs (1597)
    Novello and Company, Limited (1901.), New York
  - The Despairing Lover (Box 2, Folder 1)
    For Chorus of Men's Voices Unaccompanied
    Text: William Walsh (1663-1708)
  - In May (Box 2, Folder 1)
    For Chorus of Women's Voices, Orchestra, and Harp
    G. Schirmer, Inc. (1897), New York - Boston
  - The Lord Is My Light (Box 2, Folder 1)
    SATB and Organ
    Text: Psalm 27: Verses 1, 2, 3, 8, 11, 16
    G. Schirmer, Inc. (1918), New York - Boston
  - Now Sinks the Sun (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Chorus for SATB Unaccompanied
    Text: From "St. Christopher"
    English Translation: Isabella G. Parker
    Novello and Company, Limited (1900), New York
  - Union and Liberty Op. 60 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Patriotic Chorus for SATB and Piano
    Text: Oliver Wendell Holmes
    G. Schirmer, Inc. (1905), New York
- Reinhard G. Pauly
  Mus. M. 1948, Ph. D. 1956
  - Darkness Was Over All (Tenebrae Factae Sunt) / Transcribed by R.G. Pauly, Haydn, Michael, 1737-1806 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    For Three-Part Chorus of Women's Voices with Organ or Piano Accompaniment
    English version: Dr. Th. Baker and R.G. Pauly
    G. Schirmer, Inc. (1958), New York
  - God, In Thee I Seek My Salvation (Esto Mihi In Deum Protectorum) / Arranged by R.G. Pauly, Haydn, Michael, 1737-1806 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    For Four-Part Chorus of Mixed Voices with Organ or Piano Accompaniment
    English Translation: R.G. Pauly
  - God Is Merciful (Gradual "Confitemini Domino") / Arranged by R.G. Pauly, Haydn, Michael, 1737-1806 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - God, Our Father (Tu Es Deus) / Edited and Translated by R.G. Pauly, Eberlin, Ernst, 1702-1762 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Gradual for Quinquagesima Sunday
    For Four-Part Chorus of Mixed Voices, à cappella
    Psalm Text
    G. Schirmer, Inc. (1960), New York
  - Great Is the Lord, Our Maker (Gradual "Ecce Sacerdos") / Arranged by R.G. Pauly, Haydn, Michael, 1737-1806 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    English versions: R.G. Pauly
  - Grief Is In My Heart (Improperium exspectavit cor meum) / Edited and Translated by R.G. Pauly, Eberlin, Ernst, 1702-1762 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Offertory for Palm Sunday
  - Help Us, O Lord, Deliver Us (Gradual "Propitius esto Domine") / Arranged by R.G. Pauly, Haydn, Michael, 1737-1806 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - O Savior, Our Refuge (Adiutor in opportunitatibus) / Transcribed and Edited from the Manuscript by R.G. Pauly, Eberlin, Ernst, 1702-1762 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Gradual for Septuagesima Sunday
    Text: Psalm IX: 9-10, 18-19
    Translation by: R.G. Pauly
  - Trust In The Lord (Bonum est confiteri) / Edited from a Contemporary Manuscript and Translated by R.G. Pauly, Eberlin, Ernst, 1702-1762 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Offertory for Septuagesima Sunday
    G. Schirmer, Inc. (1960), Mew York
- Philip A. Prince
  B.A. 1952, Mus. B. 1958, Mus. M. 1959
  - O Clap Your Hands, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Anthem for Ascensiontide for Mixed Chorus (SATB) and Organ
    Text: Psalm 47: 1-2, 5-8 (Book of Common Prayer)
- Arthur Rhea
  - The Beatitudes, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    SATB, Organs Bass or Tenor Solo
    Text: St. Matthew V. I.
- Gay Hylander Rockwood
  Mus. B. 1933, Mus. M. 1934
  - Processional and Alleluia (Box 2, Folder 3)
    For Christmas or Easter Mixed Choir unaccompanied
    Oxford University Press, Inc. (1967), New York
- Charles Shackford
  B.A. 1941, Mus. B. 1942, Mus. M. 1944
  - An Ode to Learning, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    TTBB and Piano
    Text: "New England's First Fruits," 1643; "The Covenant of Grace," Thomas Shepherd, 1651
    Inscribed by composer: "Wellesley, Mass. Oct. '59"
- Albert Sly
  - Psalm 100 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    For SATB Chorus, Piano or Organ
- David Stanley Smith
  B.A. 1900, Mus. B. 1903, Faculty - 1903-1946, Dean - 1920-1940
  - All Hail to the Days (Box 2, Folder 4)
    English Melody, XVIIth Century
    Text: English Black Letter Ballad, XVIIth Century (Arranged by D.S. Smith)